

London, UK | tuyet.a.le@hotmail.co.uk | linkedin.com/in/toowee | github.com/toowee-le | toowee.dev

# **SUMMARY**

A career-changer and self-taught front-end developer who turned her enthusiasm for web development into a career.

# **SKILLS**

**Programming** HTML5 ⋅ CSS3/SCSS ⋅ Bootstrap

JavaScript ES6+ · NodeJS · ExpressJS

Tools Git/GitHub • Visual Studio Code

Heroku. • Netlify • WordPress

Design Illustrator ⋅ InDesign ⋅ XD

Others Project Management · Research

# **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

## **Udacity Front-End Web Developer Nanodegree**

Mar 2020 - current

- Building 5 projects utilising HTML, CSS, Sass, JavaScript, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Webpack and RESTful APIs
- Testing new APIs to build unique applications including a Natural Language Processing Express-Webpack app to analyse the emotions of news articles

## **Free Code Camp**

Oct 2019 - current

 Completed 10 projects for Responsive Web Design and JavaScript Algorithms & Data Structures certifications

# Code First Girls - Introduction to Python Programming in partnership with Goldman Sachs

Feb - Apr 2020

- Worked collaboratively to learn programming fundamentals in Python using PyCharm
- Successfully built a cocktail recipe back-end app utilising
  Python and a public API as the final course project

### Code First Girls - Introduction to Web Development

Oct - Dec 2019

 Awarded runner-up prize for best team website built using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery and Bootstrap

# Brunel University - BSc Psychology and Sociology

Sep 2011 - Jul 2014

First Class Honours achieved

## **PROJECTS**

# Natural Language Processing | Live Link | Github

A single-page Node Express-Webpack app that allows a computer to analyse a news article and interpret its emotions and perspectives using a NLP API.

Full portfolio: www.toowee.dev

## **EMPLOYMENT**

## **Senior Charity Administrator & Finance Officer**

Saving Faces-The Facial Surgery Research Foundation, London Mar 2017 – present

- Maintain all websites and develop web pages using semantic markup and styles built on WordPress
- Increase front-end efficiency and resolve hacking issues by switching CMS, resulting in faster content publication and increase monthly traffic by 5%-10%
- Design infographics and layouts for email campaigns for fundraising events
- Improving social media engagement by collaborating with the research team to promote new campaigns
- Support the CEO and Trustees in the governance of the charity and management of the administrative department of 3 people
- Improve office productivity by implementing Trello to streamline and set goals for daily operations

# **Honorary Clinical Researcher**

Saving Faces-The Facial Surgery Research Foundation, London Jan 2016 – Mar 2017

- Assisted statisticians and clinicians in managing 3 major national facial surgery clinical trials and audits
- Provided operational telephone support to over 50 hospitals for a new major NHS national audit
- Designed surveys to gather patient and public feedback

#### **Lead Administrator**

Chobham Academy, London

Oct 2014 - Jan 2016

- Led parent outreach by launching and designing the weekly printed newsletter improving communication, events attendance and parental engagement
- Delegated roles to a team of 3 others to increase the efficiency of the primary school office
- Maintained the primary school's CRM